Grant Sweeney

Alexandria, VA 22314 grantsweeney027_qqz@indeedemail.com +1 703 755 5452

Objective Engaging summer internship with an exciting, innovative company that will further my technical growth and business acumen to prepare me to succeed beyond expectations of future professional endeavors

Summary Accelerated rising junior at the University of Virginia studying towards a double major in Computer

Science and Computer Engineering with a potential minor in engineering business. Leader chosen by his peers in numerous academic and extracurriculars settings. Student seeking opportunities to see technology and business integrated in a notable company. Creative, analytical thinker with business mindset. Outstanding communication skills and strong ability (and recommends) to work in diverse groups from his exposure to different cultures living in Europe for 7 years for the US Military.

Work Experience

Gizmology Club of UVA January 2021 to Present

- Code with Arduino, a C/C++ dialect, to create certain patterns on LED light strips
- Used soldering methods to connect our LEDs to Arduino circuit boards
- 3D printing and laser printing to create customized nameplates

Private Tutoring

Private Tutoring January 2018 to Present

- Deliver one-on-one tutoring lessons in a wide range of subjects for multiple families
- Specialize in teaching pre-algebra, algebra, calculus, SAT Prep, and computer programming

Vice President

Model United Nations Club January 2017 to December 2021

- Organized 4 in-school debate conferences to improve members' knowledge of debate and public speaking
- Coordinated the club's attendance at college-level conferences at Georgetown University and The College of William and Mary

President Student Council

Freshman Class Ramstein High School - Ramstein, Germany January 2017 to December 2018

- Oversaw fundraising events for class events and programming
- Mobilized Ramstein's Class of 2021 to participate in school spirit events to raise morale among students

Education

BS in Computer Science & Computer Engineering

University of Virginia, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences - Charlottesville, VA $\,$ May $\,2024\,$

High school diploma

West Potomac High School - Alexandria, VA 2021

Skills

- Python programming Java programming Matlab, Autodesk Fusion, SolidWorks MS Office 360 Professional
- C/C++
- Java
- Calculus
- Algebra
- Python
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Word
- MATLAB
- AutoCAD
- Autodesk
- SolidWorks
- Tutoring
- GitHub
- Computer Science